The calibration tool, allows calibrating the video size in pixels, to the real-world size
of the objects in the video.
This, for example, allows computing the real world speed from video speed. By converting
pixel measurements to meter measurements.
The pixels per meter metadata is exported with the raw data.
To show the calibration tool, press the ruler button.
This will show two points that can be adjusted to a known real world distance.
For example, the corners are known to be eighteen inches apart.
Then, press the calibration settings button,
to show the settings.
In the distance field,
enter the real-world distance between the points, in millimeter.
Finally, press the save button
To compute, display, and save,
the pixels per meter for the video file.