Glitter supports computing statistics from the glitter coded data. It can compute
for example, the number of events of an event channel or the mean speed of a
position channel. The summery data can then be batch exported to an excel file.
Here's an example summary excel file.
From the main page, click export view, to switch to the export page.
Once in the export view page, you can generate the summaries
by selecting that mode from the dropdown menu.
Following are the overall steps to export the data, with some of them optional.
All files in the batch to be processed, must contain similar data channels. Otherwise,
they must be exported in separate batches.
Any one file from the batch, must initially be selected as a template. This template file
will be used to create summary measures using the channel names in the file and then applied
to all the files in the batch.
Select this file here.
Also select the excel file where all the data will be exported to.
Many measures accept parameters, such as a threshold or a start time.
Some of these parameters can be given global default values shared across all measures
that use them.
This section lists all these optional parameters as well as an explanation for each parameter.
For example, the end parameter can be set to 2. Then, only the first two seconds of the
video will be used in the data summaries.
Other parameters are specific to individual measures and cannot be given global default values.
This section lists all these parameters and an explanation for them.
Some measures require intermediate data channels, in addition to the user-coded channels.
For example, to compute the total time the animal's nose was in a zone. We can create an intermediate
event channel from the nose position channel and the zone channel. This channel would be active whenever
the nose is in the zone.
Then, for example, we can compute with the intermediate channel, the number of
times the nose entered the zone.
This section lets you create these intermediate channels.
To add a measure channel. First select the type of channel from which it will be created.
For example, a position channel.
Then select the measure to create
For example, the position channel is in a zone measure, mentioned above.
And click the plus button to create it.
Now, we will need to configure the channel.
From the populated list of position channel names in the template file.
Select a channel. For example the spiral channel.
Then, expand the channel options,
to show the documentation for the channel,
as well as to configure any channel parameters.
For example, from the list of zone channels
select and add the circle channel.
The intermediate channel will now create an event channel that is active,
whenever the spiral channel is within the circle zone.
Finally, give the new intermediate channel a unique name.
Glitter supports computing and exporting many common summary measures for all channel types.
For example, we can export the mean speed of a position channel, the number of active periods
and total active duration of an event channel, or the total area of a zone channel.
This section lets you create these summary measures.
To add a measure. Select the type of channel to which it will be applied and the specific measure.
And click the plus button to create it.
This measure will compute the total duration that the specified event channel was coded as active.
Next, we need to select the channels for which we will compute this in the report.
It will be computed for both the spiral and event channels.
You can also optionally add an ID to the measure that will be included with the measure in the report.
Finally, you can further configure the measure or read the measure documentation.
Next, we will select and add another measure.
This measure computes the mean distance between a position channel and the center of a zone.
From the pre-populated position channel list,
we will compute this measure for the spiral channel.
For the zone channel parameter, from the data file's list of zones,
we will select the circle zone.
Therefore, this measure will compute the mean distance between the
spiral channel and the center of the circle.
You can further read the measure documentation, or set the optional parameters.
Once we configured the measures, we can select the files in the batch.
First, select the input directory with the data files to process.
Then, select a filter with which to select the data files in that directory and sub-directories.
The shown filter will only select files that end with the h 5 extension, which is the extension of the data files.
Finally, click refresh.
Glitter will now list all the matched files that are to be processed.
To start the export process, press the play button to start exporting data from the files.
Then, the exported data will be found in the configured excel file.