Glitter lets you code behaviors, and lets you track the position of objects in a video file.
To begin, browse for a video file with the browse button.
and select a video file.
This will open the video file in glitter.
When data is coded with glitter, it stores the coded data, in a h 5 file right next to the video file.
If the data file already exists, glitter will open the data file. Otherwise it will create a new data file.
This data file is later used when computing and exporting statistics.
Glitter also creates a temporary file, in which the data is saved periodically, in
case of a program crash before the data is explicitly saved.
Once a file is opened, the full path to the video and data file currently open is shown in the title bar.
To save all unsaved data, to the h 5 file
press the save button
or, hit the control s keyboard key.
To check whether data is unsaved.
The presence of an asterisk in the title bar indicates that some of the data is currently unsaved.
Additionally, a prompt is shown before closing, if data is unsaved.
Glitter supports additional data operations through the drop-down menu.
It supports saving normally,
as well as saving any changes to a new h 5 file, leaving the currently open data file unchanged.
It can open a video and data file in read only mode. Such that no changes can be saved to that file.
It can remove any unsaved changes and reset to the last saved state
or close the currently open file altogether.
It can import all the channels metadata from an existing data file, without also importing the coded channel data.
To facilitate sharing a template with all the channels, without the channel data.
The channels metadata can be exported to a special yaml file and shared with others.
Others can then import these channels from the yaml file.
As a convenience, the most recent yaml template imported is listed in the menu.
And it can be imported again without having to browse for it.