Glitter supports importing c s v files that contain coded data exported by other programs.
Demo c s v files can be found in the source code.
From within the import section.
First, select the c s v importing mode from the drop down menu.
Then, select the output directory, where the glitter h 5 data files that are generated
from the c s v files, will be created.
Next, select the input directory containing the c s v files to process.
This directory should optionally contain the video files that was used to generate the c s v files.
Glitter needs these video files if the input c s v files do not contain data for all video frames.
Then, select a filter with which to select the c s v files in that directory and sub-directories.
The shown filter will only select files that end with the c s v extension.
Finally, click refresh.
Glitter will now list all the matched files and they are ready to be processed as described in the
main import guide.