Glitter supports importing t x t files that contain coded data exported by the Clever System program.
Demo t x t files can be found in the source code.
From within the import section.
First, select the Clever System importing mode from the drop down menu.
Next, select the output directory, where the glitter h 5 data files that are generated
from the t x t files, will be created.
Then, select the input directory containing the t x t files to process.
This directory must also contain the video files used to generate the t x t files, because
the video files are needed by glitter to generate the h 5 files.
Next, select the filter with which to select the t x t files in that directory and sub-directories.
The shown filter will only select files that end with the t x t extension.
Finally, click refresh.
Glitter will now list all the matched files and they are ready to be processed as described in the
main import guide.
Only the t c r files should be selected, because they contain the data. However, the t c g files
should also be in that directory, if they exist, because they will then be used to import the zones.