Position channels code the position of objects across video frames. For example, it could code the center
or nose of the animal.
The coded data can later be exported as raw data or summarized. For example, it can export
the mean speed of the animal, or the mean distance to a point.
Much of the channel management for position channels, is the same as for event channels.
Please see the event channel guide.
To code a channel, first select the channel.
Now the channel can be coded with the mouse.
A position channel can also be selected with an assigned keyboard key, such as n in this example.
Once selected, while the video is playing, follow the position of the object with the mouse pressed down. This
will code the position for the current video frames.
The recent position history of the tracked object can be shown, if enabled.
Press the history button to show or hide the position history.
Normally, the player will continuously show new frames to code.
However, by setting the frame rate to the minimum,
the player shows a single frame, and only advances to the next frame, when the mouse is pressed to code the frame.
This allows more accurate coding.