Zone channels code the position of static objects in the video. For example, it could code the position of
odors to be sniffed.
The coded data can later be exported as raw data or summarized. For example, it can export
the area of the zone, or the duration the animal was in the zone, if coded.
Much of the channel management for zone channels, is the same as for event channels.
Please see the event channel guide.
However, unlike event channels, zone channels are added by drawing them.
To draw a zone, first enable showing the zones,
then, enable editing the zones.
The type of zone created, is controlled by the zone mode selected. The default is freeform.
To draw a freeform polygon,
drag the mouse over the area to enclose.
To draw a more precise polygon,
place polygon vertices by pressing the mouse on each point. To finish, double click the mouse.
The zone can be edited by slow-pressing a vertex and dragging it. The overall zone can be dragged,
when not editing it, by dragging the first point.
To draw an ellipse,
drop the ellipse center with the mouse. Then, edit it, by dragging the points on the radius.
To draw a circle,
drop the circle center with the mouse. Then, edit it, by dragging the point on the radius.
To place a single point,
drop the point with the mouse. It can be edited, by dragging the point.
The zones can be hidden or shown, by toggling the display button.
To either show them.
Or hide them